Guide to the Tau Epsilon Phi, Delta Upsilon Chapter (Duke University) Records, 1957-1981
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Tau Epsilon Phi, Delta Upsilon Chapter (Duke University) records 1957-1981
University Archives, Duke University
Tau Epsilon Phi. Delta Upsilon Chapter (Duke University).
0.5 Linear Feet about 200 Items
The Delta Upsilon Chapter of the Tau Epsilon Phi fraternity was established at Duke University in April 1952. It disbanded in 1981.
Types of material include correspondence, minutes, reports, rosters, newsletters, printed material, and clippings. Major topics include student life at Duke University, housing arrangements for campus groups, and general management of a fraternal organization. The bulk of materials are from 1970-1976.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advanced notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Tau Epsilon Phi, Delta Upsilon Chapter (Duke University) Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1980.
Historical Note
The Delta Upsilon chapter of Tau Epsilon Phi was established at Duke University on April 26, 1952, with the goal of promoting friendship among male students. The chapter later expanded its goals to include brotherly friendship with female students. In 1976, they followed other Tau Epsilon Phi chapters and chose to accept women as members. Three women joined the chapter under an associate brother program. Citing the desire to conform to national rules, the associate brother program was discontinued and replaced with a little sister program in 1979. Fraternity members and the Duke University Interfraternity Council cited many conflicts with the co-educational membership. Membership sharply decreased during the late 1970s until there were only six active members by fall of 1981. The Delta Upsilon chapter lost their on-campus housing in September 1980 due to low membership and lack of pledges. The chapter disbanded in 1981.
Collection Overview
Types of material include correspondence, minutes, reports, rosters, newsletters, printed material, and clippings. Major topics include student life at Duke University, housing arrangements for campus groups, and general management of a fraternal organization. The bulk of materials are from 1970-1976.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Tau Epsilon Phi. Delta Upsilon Chapter (Duke University)
Duke University -- Societies, etc.
Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.
Greek letter societies -- North Carolina -- Durham
Initiations (into trades, societies, etc.)
Duke University -- Housing
Related Material
Photograph Collection
Duke University Archives
Interfraternity Council Records
Duke University Archives
Fraternities and Sororities Collection
Duke University Archives
Panhellenic Council Records
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Correspondence, 1967-1979 (Box 1)
  - "Purpose of T.E.P" and "T.E.P. Sister Proposal"
  - Social events, circa 1972
  - Executive Board minutes, May 1978-August 1978
  - Chancellor's reports, 1972, 1975
  - Miscellaneous financial materials, 1970-1978
  - Pledge lists, circa 1970-1974
  - Membership roster, circa 1970-1974
  - Housing lists, circa 1972-1976
  - Interfraternity Council meeting minutes, 1973-1978
  - Newsletters, 1972-1978
  - Printed materials, 1957-1979
  - Clippings, 1979-1981